<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="Interfacing Reality">
        <intro 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/reality/tcheatst.html">
                <description>
                What good is a brain if you can't touch the world? This cheatsheet 
                will help you with running models that can interact.
                </description>
        </intro>
<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/core/runtime.html"
                skip="true"
                title="jACT-R Runtime">
                <description>
                All models exist within an ACTRRuntime. It controls their
                executions, as well as the interactions with the simulated world. The 'real-world'
                is inturn controlled by the RealityInterface and its slew of delegate components
                that slice up and represent the world to the models. 
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/core/ext.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Model Extensions">
                <description>
                Extensions provide the entry point for functionality into a model. For instance,
                the VisualExtension adds the functionality required for the model to encode and process
                visual information in an abstract and common way. <br/>
                A model simulating basic HCI issues would use the VisualExtension, ManualExtension, and perhaps
                the AuditoryExtension (if it existed yet). But that is just on the model side.
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/core/interface.html"
                skip="true"
                title="jACT-R Reality Interface Components">
                <description>
                The model can now see and manipulate things. But it needs to be able to
                interface with the world itself. These components parcel external information (e.g. video-feed,
                screen dump, radar or network packet data) into formats that are specified by the
                various Extensions. <br/>
                In this way models and the worlds within which they interact can be more easily
                modified to fit technological needs.<br/>
                For our model to see and touch the computer, the RealityInterface would install
                the SwingRealityInterfaceComponent. This will allow it to interact with most Java
                applications. 
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/core/clock.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Time Control">
                <description>
                Many models running in the same environment, simulated or not, will
                have to execute according to the same laws of time. The RealityInterface
                also controls the central Clock object. <br/>
                
                <b>Realtime</b> clocks are just that. All models run no faster than real-time. 
                Odd things can happen if the models cannot run faster than realtime.<br/>
                <b>Shared</b> clocks force all the running models to move in semi-lock-step such that
                the firing of their productions are synchronous (in terms of simulation). <br/>
                <br/>
                Shared clocks are to be preferred.
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/using/ext.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Models & Extensions">
                <description>
                Different syntaxes will have different means of installing extensions
                into the model. The quickest way is to just create a new model via the 
                New ACT-R Model wizard. Be sure to select the Extensions you want installed. You
                can set any configuration parameters in the neighboring panel.
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/using/interface.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Reality Interface">
                <description>
                A model with the VisualExtension installed will need to have appropriate 
                interface components enabled. This is done in the run configuration for a model.
                <br/>
                <b>Run->Run..</b>. Select <b>ACT-R Model->New Model..</b>.<br/>
                The <b>Interfaces</b> tab allows you to select the interface components and
                set their parameters.
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/using/interface.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Clock">
                <description>
                A model with the VisualExtension installed will need to have appropriate 
                interface components enabled. This is done in the run configuration for a model.
                <br/>
                <b>Run->Run..</b>. Select <b>ACT-R Model->New Model..</b>.<br/>
                The <b>Interfaces</b> tab allows you to select the interface components and
                set their parameters.
                </description>
</item>

<item 
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/using/clock.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Clock">
                <description>
                The <b>Clock</b> tab allows you to enable the realtime clock for whatever reason.
                </description>
</item>


<item
                href="/org/jactr/eclipse/using/output.html"
                skip="true"
                title="Model Output">
                <description>
                The <b>runs/{timestamp}/{run-configuration}.env</b> contains the complete configuration
                for running the selected models. 
                </description>
</item>
</cheatsheet>